A Guide to the Jean Elliott Papers, 1999-2015
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Jean Elliott Papers, 1999-2015
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2016-014
1.04 Cubic Feet
The Jean Elliott Papers includes documents and correspondence relating to Jean Elliott's work within the LGBTQ community at Virginia Tech.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Jean Elliott Papers were donated to Special Collections in 2015.
Biographical Note
Jean Elliott worked for Virgina Tech from 1999-2015. She retired in 2015 as Communications Manager for the Virginia Tech College of Liberal Arts and Sciences. Prior to working at Virginia Tech, Elliott served as the Sports Information Director at the College of William and Mary and Brown University.
As an employee of Virginia Tech, Elliott was a visible advocate for the LGBTQ community. In 2005, she worked with professors Jeff Mann and Carol Burch-Brown to establish the annual "Gay in Appalachia" event, which celebrates the LGBTQ+ experience in rural communities through visual and performing arts. In 2009, Elliott worked with the LGBT faculty/staff caucus to establish an Ally of the Year Award and the Lavender Commencement Ceremony for LGBTQ+ students at Virginia Tech.
Elliott has been recognized for her work advocacy work by Equality Virginia, which named her an "Outstanding Virginian" in 2012. Elliott received the Presidential Principles of Community Award, Virginia Tech's highest honor for diversity and inclusion work, in 2014.
Sources:
http://www.equalityvirginia.org/dinner-2016/outstanding-virginians/jean-elliott/
http://www.roanoke.com/news/education/higher_education/virginia_tech/longtime-virginia-tech-diversity-advocate-retires-to-nature-and-family/article_685e5819-16ec-5e36-ad8a-60a026f72f89.html
Scope and Content
The Jean Elliott Papers includes documents and correspondece relating to Jean Elliott's work within the LGBTQ Community at Virginia Tech. A few documents also relate to the College of William and Mary, where she worked prior to Virginia Tech. The collection consists of information about the LGBTQ community and resources for students, LGBTQ event planning and LGBTQ events at Virginia Tech, including "Gay in Appalachia" and the Lavender Commencement Ceremony, as well as correspondence with other LGBTQ Caucus members and government officials.
Index Terms
Subjects:
LGBTQ history; Sexual minorities; Faculty; University History; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
- Ally List (Box-folder 1-1)
- Ally of the Year Award, 2010 (Box-folder 1-2)
- Articles
  - "The Bible and Homosexuality: A Christian View", 2006 (Box-folder 1-3)
  - "Genocidal Intentions: Social Death and the Ex-Gay Movement" (Box-folder 1-4)
- Assessments
  - Assessment of Campus Climate for LGBTQ, 2012 (Box-folder 1-5)
  - Assessment of Diversity Issues and Constituent Groups, 2011 (Box-folder 1-6)
- Board of Visitors
  - Board of Visitors Meeting, March 2003 (Box-folder 1-7)
  - Board of Visitors Press Copy, March 2003 (Box-folder 1-8)
  - Board of Visitors Summary, March 2003 (Box-folder 1-9)
  - Board of Visitors Meeting, April 2003 (Box-folder 1-10)
- Budgets and Invoices (Box-folder 1-11)
- United States 4th Circuit Case Summary, 1999 (Box-folder 1-12)
- Center for Equal Opportunity (Box-folder 1-13)
- Comparison of Tuition and Fees>, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 1-14)
- Consortium of Higher Education (Box-folder 1-15)
- Contracts (Box-folder 1-16)
- Correspondence
  - Dorothy Allison and Jeff Mann, 2009 (Box-folder 1-17)
  - Danny Axsom, 2008 (Box-folder 1-18)
  - Kenneth Belcher, 2007-2009 (Box-folder 1-19)
  - Jeremy Billetdeaux, 2006 (Box-folder 1-20)
  - E. Gail Billingsley, 2007 (Box-folder 1-21)
  - John T. Casteen III, 2007-2010 (Box-folder 1-22)
  - Tanyah Cotton and Gaye Adegbalola, 2013 (Box-folder 1-23)
  - Danielle Currier, 2007 (Box-folder 1-24)
  - Mary Dunkenberger, 2010 (Box-folder 1-25)
  - Ross Edmonds, 2008 (Box-folder 1-26)
  - Amber D. Evans, 2007 (Box-folder 1-27)
  - Ken Gideon, 2001 (Box-folder 1-28)
  - George Greenia, 2001 (Box-folder 1-29)
  - Gwen Harrington, 2007 (Box-folder 1-30)
  - Carola A. Haas, 2001 (Box-folder 1-31)
  - Bradley Hertel, 2007 (Box-folder 1-32)
  - William Hurd, 2002 (Box-folder 1-33)
  - David Johnson, 2003 (Box-folder 1-34)
  - Grace Yia-Hei Kao, 2007 (Box-folder 1-35)
  - Claire N. Kaplan, 2001 (Box-folder 1-36)
  - Anna Kilkelly, 2007 (Box-folder 1-37)
  - Carrie Kline, 2006 (Box-folder 1-38)
  - Anna LoMascolo, 2007 (Box-folder 1-39)
  - Kevin McDonald, 2008-2009 (Box-folder 1-40)
  - Multiple Individuals, 2006-2009 (Box-folder 1-41)
  - Fred Piercy,2007 (Box-folder 1-42)
  - Ellen Plummer2006 (Box-folder 1-43)
  - Sue Rankin, 2011 (Box-folder 1-44)
  - Christine Robinson, 2010 (Box-folder 1-45)
  - Guy Simes, 2008-2009 (Box-folder 1-46)
  - Lou Ann Slageln.d. (Box-folder 1-47)
  - Charles Steger, 2009-2010 (Box-folder 1-48)
  - Mat Stoll, 2007 (Box-folder 1-49)
  - Unknown Individuals, 2001-2009 (Box-folder 1-50)
  - Susan Verbrugge, 2007 (Box-folder 1-51)
  - Bob Witeck, 2009 (Box-folder 1-52)
  - Najma Yousem, 2007 (Box-folder 1-53)
- Diversity Committee (Box-folder 1-54)
- Diversity Summit (Box-folder 1-55)
- Domestic Partnership Information (Box-folder 1-56)
- Equality Virginia (Box-folder 1-57)
- Events
  - "For the Bible Tells Me So"2007 (Box-folder 1-58)
  - "Revelations"2006 (Box-folder 1-59)
- Facility Admission Policy (Box-folder 1-60)
- Gay in Appalachia
  - 4th - 8th Annual Gay in Appalachia, 2008-2012 (Box-folder 1-61)
  - 9th - 11th Annual Gay in Appalachia2013-2015 (Box-folder 1-62)
- Gender Diversity (Box-folder 1-63)
- Incidents of Bias and Discrimination (Box-folder 1-64)
- Lambda (Box-folder 1-65)
- Lavender Commencement Ceremonies, 2009-2015 (Box-folder 1-66)
- LGBTQ
  - LGBTQ Advisory Board (Box-folder 1-67)
  - LGBTQ Caucus Meetings and Reports (Box-folder 1-68)
  - LGBTQ Caucus Picnic, 2008 (Box-folder 1-69)
  - LGBTQ Centers (Box-folder 1-70)
  - LGBTQ Coordinator Position (Box-folder 1-71)
  - LGBTQ History (Box-folder 1-72)
  - Hokie Hi Welcome, 2012 (Box-folder 1-73)
  - LGBTQ Inclusive Courses (Box-folder 1-74)
  - LGBTQ Issues and Policies (Box-folder 1-75)
  - LGBTQ Leadership (Box-folder 1-76)
  - LGBTQ Scholarship (Box-folder 1-77)
  - LGBTQ Resource Centers (Box-folder 1-78)
  - LGBTQ Survery Questions (Box-folder 1-79)
- Magazines
  - The Interloper, 2014 (Box-folder 1-80)
  - The Virginia Tech Magazine, 2003 (Box-folder 1-81)
- Mission and Vision Statements of Virginia Tech (Box-folder 1-82)
- Multicultural Faculty and Staff Luncheon (Box-folder 1-83)
- Newspapers
  - The Chronicle of Higher Education, 2002-2003 (Box-folder 1-84)
  - Collegiate Times, 2004-2013 (Box-folder 1-85)
  - The Roanoke Times, 2004-2014 (Box-folder 1-86)
  - The Virginia Tech Conductor, 2006 (Box-folder 1-87)
  - Newspaper Clipping, 2009 (Box-folder 1-88)
- Plus One and Other Qualified Adult Coverage (Box-folder 1-90)
- Race Neutral Approaches (Box-folder 1-91)
- Rally at William and Mary (Box-folder 1-92)
- Research Universities (Box-folder 1-93)
- Resolutions and Constitutions2008-2009 (Box-folder 1-94)
- Safe Watch (Box-folder 1-95)
- Safe Zone (Box-folder 1-96)
- Safe Zone at William and Mary (Box-folder 1-97)
- Symposiums
  - "And Justice For All" KU1998 (Box-folder 1-98)
  - "And Justice For All" VCU2011 (Box-folder 1-99)
  - "Cultivating Peace"2010 (Box-folder 1-100)
  - "Network VA" (Box-folder 1-101)
- The Stories Project (Box-folder 1-102)
- Women and Minority Artists and Scholars Lecture Series2006-2013 (Box-folder 1-103)